{
    "questions": 
    [
        {
            "question": "What is capital of Russia",
            "answers": ["Moscow", "Kiev", "Baku", "Minsk"],
            "correct": "Moscow"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the largest country in the world",
            "answers": ["Canada", "USA", "Russia", "China"],
            "correct": "Russia"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following countries has a population exceeding 100 million",
            "answers": ["Germany", "Saudi Arabia", "Pakistan", "Canada"],
            "correct": "Pakistan"
        },
        {
            "question": "Muscat is the capital of which country",
            "answers": ["Yemen", "Oman", "Kuwait", "Bahrain"],
            "correct": "Oman"
        },
        {
            "question": "With how many countries does Austria border",
            "answers": ["6", "7", "8", "9"],
            "correct": "8"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which river flows through Innsbruck",
            "answers": ["Inn", "Donau", "Mur", "Una"],
            "correct": "Inn"
        },
        {
            "question": "The great Victoria Desert is located in",
            "answers": ["Canada", "Saudi Arabia", "Australia", "China"],
            "correct": "Australia"
        },
        {
            "question": "The intersecting lines drawn on maps and globes are",
            "answers": ["latitudes", "longitudes", "geographic grids", "lamnitudes"],
            "correct": "geographic grid"
        },
        {
            "question": "The habitats valuable for commercially harvested species are called",
            "answers": ["coral reefs", "sea grass bed", "hot spots", "green planktons"],
            "correct": "sea grass bed"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is tropical grassland",
            "answers": ["Taiga", "Savannah", "Pampas", "Prairies"],
            "correct": "Savannah"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the only coastline town in Bosnia and Herzegovina",
            "answers": ["Neum", "Grude", "Mostar", "Trebinje"],
            "correct": "Neum"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many regions (zupanije and city status) does Croatia have",
            "answers": ["23", "19", "21", "18"],
            "correct": "21"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the highest peak in Croatia",
            "answers": ["Vaganski vrh", "Sveti Jure", "Kamesnica", "Dinara (Sinjal)"],
            "correct": "Dinara (Sinjal)"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which country is the source of the river Una",
            "answers": ["Bosnia and Herzegovina", "Serbia", "Slovenia", "Croatia"],
            "correct": "Croatia"
        },
        {
            "question": "How long is the rivel Nile in km",
            "answers": ["6,853", "7,145", "7,096", "6,983"],
            "correct": "6,853"
        },
        {
            "question": "The iron and steel industries of which of the following countries are almost fully dependent on imported raw materials",
            "answers": ["Britain", "Japan", "Poland", "Germany"],
            "correct": "Japan"
        },
        {
            "question": "The temperature increases rapidly after",
            "answers": ["ionosphere", "exosphere", "stratosphere", "troposphere"],
            "correct": "ionosphere"
        },
        {
            "question": "The humidity of the air depends upon",
            "answers": ["temperature", "location", "weather", "all of the mentioned"],
            "correct": "all of the mentioned"
        },
        {
            "question": "The groundwater can become confined between two impermeable layers. This type of enclosed water is called",
            "answers": ["artesian", "artesian well", "unconfined groundwater", "confined groundwater"],
            "correct": "Neum"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the smallest municipality (by population) in Bosnia and Herzegovina",
            "answers": ["Juzni Doboj", "Istocni Drvar", "Kalinovik", "Trnovo"],
            "correct": "Istocni Drvar"
        },
        {
            "question": "The largest glaciers are",
            "answers": ["mountain glaciers", "alpine glaciers", "continental glaciers", "piedmont glaciers"],
            "correct": "continental glaciers"
        },
        {
            "question": "The leading state in producing paper is",
            "answers": ["Bihar", "West Bengal", "Kerala", "Orissa"],
            "correct": "West Bengal"
        }
    ]
}